Guide to the South Asian Pamphlets Collection, 1920-2005 (bulk 1950-2000) RL.01235
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- India Pamphlets, 1920-2005, bulk 1960-1990, 177 boxes
  - Education, 1927-1990, 24 boxes
    - Teacher Training, 1927-1981, 3 boxes
      - Manukhta: The Essence of Education. Peace, M. L. Jullundur, M. L. Peace and Rattan Kaur, India: 196-? (Box IN-62)
      - Map Reading. Renjen, M. L. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1963. (Box IN-62)
        Social Studies Unit.
      - Mathematics for Primary Schools: A Handbook for Teachers, Class I. NCERT Mathematics Study Group, IIT Kanpur. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1970. (Box IN-62)
      - Mathematics for Primary Schools: A Handbook for Teachers, Class II. National Council of Educational Research and Training Mathematics Group, Kanpur. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1970. (Box IN-62)
      - Memorandum of Association and Rules. National Council Of Educational Research And Training. Delhi, Publication Unit, India: 1961. (Box IN-62)
      - Methods of Teaching. Central Board of Workers' Education, Nagpur. Nagpur, Central Board for Workers' Education, India: 1966. (Box IN-62)
      - Milky Way, The. State Institute of Education, Bhubaneshwar. Bhubaneshwar, India: 1968. (Box IN-62)
      - My Experiments in Teacher Education. Mathur, V. S. Jullundur, Punjab Kitab Ghar, India: 1969. (Box IN-62)
      - National & State Councils for Teacher Education. National Council of Teacher Educators, Delhi. Delhi, National Association of Teacher Educators, India: 1965. (Box IN-62)
      - Organizing Agricultural Circle. Nat'l Council of Educational Research and Training. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1964. (Box IN-62)
        School Defence Corps Programme- No. 2.
      - Organizing Commerce Circle. Gupta, M. R. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1964. (Box IN-62)
        School Defence Corps Programme- No. 4.
      - Organizing History Circle. Dept. of Curriculum, Methods and Training, Delhi. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1964. (Box IN-62)
        School Defence Crops Programme- No. 5.
      - Organizing Social Studies Circle. Nat'l Council of Educational Research and Training. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1963. (Box IN-62)
        School Defence Corps Programme- No. 1.
      - Organizing Young Technicians Circle. Nat'l Council of Educational Research and Training. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1964. (Box IN-62)
        School Defence Corps Programme- No. 3.
      - Pilot Project on Job Analysis for Development of Technician Education & Training Programmes, A. Panjwani, S. S. Calcutta, Technical Teachers' Training Institute, India: 1971. (Box IN-62)
      - Planning for Effective Science Teaching. Sharma, R. C., Regional College of Education, Bhopal. Bhopal, National Council of Educational Research and Training, Ministry of Education, Govt. of India, India: 1969. (Box IN-62)
      - Primary Teacher Education Curriculum. Rao, C. S. Subba, and Singh, K. R. P. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1970. (Box IN-62)
      - Regional College of Education, Bhopal: Retrospects and Prospects, 1964 to 1968. National Council of Educational Research and Training, New Delhi. New Delhi, India: 1968. (Box IN-62)
      - Revised Syllabus for Junior Basic Teachers Training Course. Punjab. Chandigarh, India: 1964. (Box IN-62)
      - Secondary School Teachers in India: A Survey (Part One). National Institute of Education, National Council of Educational Research and Training. NewDelhi, India: 1971. (Box IN-177 (oversize))
        Analysis of school schedules, 1969-1970.
      - Survey of Secondary School Teachers in India. National Council of Educational Research and Training, New Delhi. New Delhi, Data Processing & Educational Survey Unit, India: 1971. (Box IN-63)
        Reaction of Teachers Towards Teaching Profession - A Study, 1969-70.
      - Syllabus for Job and Refresher Course for Mukhya Sevikas (Women Social Education Organisers). India. Ministry of Community Development and Co-operation. New Delhi, Dept. of Community Development, India: 1961. (Box IN-63)
      - Syllabus for Job-Training of Block Development Officers. India. Ministry of Community Development and Co-operation. New Delhi, Dept. of Community Development, India: 1961. (Box IN-63)
      - Symposium on Offerings and Requirements in Polytechnic Education. Technical Teachers' Training Institute, Calcutta. Calcutta, India: 1968. (Box IN-63)
      - Synopses of Experimental Project Reports. Goyal, J. C., and Duggal, Janak. New Delhi, Dept. of Teacher Education, National Institute of Education, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 196-? (Box IN-63)
      - Teacher's Guide to First Book. Rege, K. B., and Mathur, R. S. New Delhi, Directorate of Adult Education, Ministry of Education and Social Welfare, Govt. of India, India: 1974. (Box IN-63)
        Farmers Functional Literacy Programme. An experimental project of problem oriented materials.
      - Teacher's Handbook of Social Studies for Class I and II. National Council of Educational Research and Training, New Delhi. New Delhi, India: 1969. (Box IN-63)
      - Teaching English. Bhattacharyya, C. Bhubaneshwar, Regional College of Education, India: 1970. (Box IN-63)
      - Teaching in Single Teacher Schools. Chickermane, D. V. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1974. (Box IN-63)
      - Teaching of Educational Psychology. Central Institute of Education, National Council of Educational Research and Training. [Delhi], National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 196? (Box IN-63)
      - Technology for Education. Aiya, S. V. C. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1971. (Box IN-63)
      - Tools of Teaching. Nagpur, Central Board for Workers' Education, India: 1967. (Box IN-63)
      - Training Teachers of Science. All India Association of Teachers' Colleges, Delhi. Delhi, India: 1964. (Box IN-63)
      - Try Out and Standardisation of a Teacher Efficiency Inventory (in Gujarati). Patel, A. S., Bhattacharya, S. and Shah, M. M. Baroda, Centre of Advanced Study in Education, India: 1966. (Box IN-63)
    - Vocational, 1960-1989, 2 boxes
      Published by official government agencies, colleges, universities and educational associations, these 32 pamphlets offer information on the arts, commerce, engineering, teaching librarianship, medical education, education management, architecture and agriculture.
      - Annotated Bibliography on Inspection and Supervision. National Institute of Education, New Delhi. New Delhi, India: 1968. (Box IN-64)
      - Bibliography on Inspection and Supervision. National Institute of Education, New Delhi. New Delhi, India: 1968. (Box IN-64)
      - Careers in Arts and Commerce Graduates. India. Ministry of Labour, Employment and Rehabilitation. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1969. (Box IN-64)
        Career Information series: 4.
      - Careers in Engineering And Technology. India. Ministry of Labour, Employment and Rehabilitation. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1970. (Box IN-64)
        Career Information series: 1.
      - Careers in High/Higher Secondary School Leavers. India. Ministry of Labour, Employment and Rehabilitation. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1970. (Box IN-64)
        Career Information series: 2.
      - Comparative Study of the Achievements of Pupils of Academic and Diversified Courses, A. Rao, R. Srinivasa, and Arunajatai, V. Madras, The S.I.T.U. Council of Educational Research, India: 1970. (Box IN-64)
      - Education for Librarianship - A Survey. Chakravarty, N. C. Calcutta, Albert Hall, India: 1966. (Box IN-64)
        IASLIC Technical Pamphlet No.2.
      - Educational Wastage at the Primary Level: A Handbook for Teachers. Rawat, D. S., and Gupta, S. L. New Delhi, National Council of Education Research and Training, India: 1970. (Box IN-64)
      - English Version of Kannada Type-Writing Syllabus Approved by the Board for Commerce Education and Examinations. Jevoor, S. V. Bangalore, Govt. of Mysore, India: 1966. (Box IN-64)
        Mysore Government Commerce Examinations.
      - Facilities for Medical Education in India for Students of Tripura. Bureau of Educational & Vocational Guidance, Govt. of Tripura, Agartala. Agartala, Bureau of Educational and Vocational Guidance, Govt. of Tripura, India: 1967. (Box IN-64)
        Monograph No.5, 2d ed.
      - Facilities for Technical Education in Mysore State. Mysore. Mysore, Dept. of Technical Education, India: 1965. (Box IN-64)
      - Forestry as a Career. Maharashtra. Institute of Vocational Studies. Bombay, India: 1960. (Box IN-64)
      - Guide to Education in India. India. Ministry of Education. Delhi, The Ministry, India: 1970. (Box IN-64)
        Education, Law, Journalism.
      - Handbook of Management Education. Association of Indian Universities, New Delhi. New Delhi, Association of Indian Universities, India: 1989. (Box IN-65)
      - Indian Participants Trained Abroad in Agriculture and Allied Fields. India. Ministry of Food, Agriculture, Community Development and Cooperation. Bombay, Foreign Aid Division, India: 1973. (Box IN-65)
        Third Evaluation study.
      - Management Development Programmes. Administrative Staff College of India, Hyderabad. Hyderabad, India: 1974. (Box IN-65)
      - Management Education in India: 1947-1965. Pylee, M. V. [New Delhi], India: 1965? (Box IN-65)
        IRA Management Pamphlet -4.
      - Panjab University Library: Department of Library Science (Chandigarh): Prospectus for 1970-1971. Panjab University, Chandigarh. Chandigarh, Panjab University, India: 1970. (Box IN-65)
      - Post-Graduate Course for the Bachelor's Degree in Library Science: Prospectus. University of Bombay. Bombay, University of Bombay, India: 1965. (Box IN-65)
      - S.S.C. - What next? Maharashtra. Institute of Vocational Studies. Bombay, Institute of Vocational Guidance and Selection, India: 1965. (Box IN-65)
        Publication No. 2 (Seventh Edition).
      - School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi: Prospectus. School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi. New Delhi, Indraprastha Estate, India: 1964. (Box IN-65)
      - Seminar on Primary and Work-Oriented Education. National Council of Educational Research and Training. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1970. (Box IN-65)
        Commission Room 'H', Vigyan Bhavan, New Delhi.
      - Shreemati Nathibai Damodar Thackeresey Women's University, Bombay :Courses of Studies for the Examination in Library Science. Shri Hansraj Pragji Thackersey School of Library Science, Bombay. Bombay, Shri Hansraj Thackersey School of Library Science, India: 1961. (Box IN-65)
        Courses of studies for the Examination for the diploma in Library Science.
      - State Bureaus of Educational and Vocational Guidance (A Survey Report). Odgers, John G. New Delhi, NCERT-DEPSE, India: 1962. (Box IN-65)
      - Teaching Typewriting. Sreenivasan, K. R. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1965. (Box IN-65)
      - Training for Skill. Pense, S. G. Delhi, Ministry of Education, Govt. of India, India: 1967. (Box IN-65)
        (Publication No. 798).
      - Training of Resource Personnel for Experimental Projects. National Council of Educational Research and Training. New Delhi, Dept. of Teacher Education, India: 1973. (Box IN-65)
        Report of Workshop held at R.C.E. Ajmer, Dec. 4-9, 1972.
      - Training: Retrospect and Prospect. Rangnekar, Sharu S. [Calcutta], Information Research Academy, India: 1972. (Box IN-65)
        IRA Management Pamphlet - 6.
      - U.P. College of Veterinary Science and Animal Husbandry, Mathura Calendar (1968-1969). U.P. College of Veterinary Science and Animal Husbandry, Mathura. Allahabad, India: 1968. (Box IN-65)
      - U.P. College of Veterinary Science and Animal Husbandry, Mathura Calendar (1969-1970). U.P. College of Veterinary Science and Animal Husbandry, Mathura. Allahabad, India: 1969. (Box IN-65)
      - Vocational Education for Farm Youth (Teacher's Handbook). Dept. of Agriculture, Regional College of Education, Bhubaneswar. New Delhi, National Council of Educational Research and Training, India: 1971. (Box IN-65)
      - Vocationalisation of Secondary Education. University of Agricultural Sciences, Bangalore. Bangalore, University of Agricultural Sciences, India: 1969. (Box IN-65)
        U.A.S. Misc. Series No.12.
  - Elections, 1957-1989, 1 box
    The 28 pamphlets in this section were published by the Election Commission of India and political parties between 1957 and 1989. This collection includes a rare pamphlet on archives and provincial polls from 1937-1946, electoral propaganda, rules and regulations for elections, guidelines for election workers, campaigns, statistical information of various elections, state legislatures, Indian parliament, electoral reform and analyses of voting behavior.
    - Archives and the Provincial Polls: 1937 and 1946. National Archives of India. New Delhi, India: 1980. (Box IN-66)
      Exhibition of Original Documents and Contemporary Photographs, 1st to 3rd June 1980.
    - Democracy in Action: World Press on Indian Elections, 1967. Ministry of External Affairs. New Delhi, Govt. of India, India: 1967. (Box IN-66)
    - Election and Democracy. Sarva Seva Sangh Prakashan. Varanasi, India: 1967. (Box IN-66)
    - Election Do's and Don'ts. Bhandari, Dharmendra. Jaipur, University of Rajasthan, India: 198-? (Box IN-66)
    - Election Guide for Candidates & Workers. Indian National Congress. New Delhi, India: 1971. (Box IN-66)
    - Election Law and Rules - Technique and Propaganda. Sen, A. K. New Delhi, Indian National Congress Committee, India: 1968. (Box IN-66)
    - Election Review and Party's Tasks. Calcutta, India: 1967. (Box IN-66)
      Adopted by the Central Committee of the Communist Party of India (Marxist) at its Session in Calcutta, April 10 to 16, 1967.
    - Fight Communal Danger, Defend National Unity, Defeat Congress (I). Surjeet, Harkishan Singh. Delhi, Communist Party of India (Marxist), India: 1989. (Box IN-66)
      CPI(M) Election Campaign Pamphlet Series. No.3.
    - General Elections: Appeal to Electorate. All India Lawyers Union. Delhi, India: 1989. (Box IN-66)
    - General Elections 1967: Instructions to Presiding Officers. Election Commission of India. Madhupatna, India: 1967. (Box IN-66)
    - Hand Book for Countiing Agents. Election Commission of India. New Delhi, India: 1982. (Box IN-66)
    - Hand Book for Polling Agents. India. Election Commission of India. New Delhi, Election Commission of India, India: 1982. (Box IN-66)
    - India Goes to the Polls. Ministry of Information and Broadcasting. New Delhi, India: 1971. (Box IN-66)
    - India States Go to the Polls. Ministry of Information and Broadcasting. New Delhi, India: 1972. (Box IN-66)
    - Kerala Mid-term Election, 1970: An Analysis. All India Congress Committee. New Delhi, India: 1970. (Box IN-66)
    - Lok Sabha Election Reportage - 1989. Department of Public Relations. Trivandrum, Government of Kerala, India: 1989. (Box IN-66)
    - Manifesto of Swami Satyabhakt, Candidate for Presidentship Election. Satyabhakt, Swami. Ayodhya, India: 1967. (Box IN-66)
    - Model Code of Conduct for the Guidance of Political Parties and Candidates. Trivedi, R. K. New Delhi, Election Commission of India, India: 1984. (Box IN-66)
    - People's Victory: An Analysis of 1971 Elections. All India Congress Committee. New Delhi, India: 1971. (Box IN-66)
    - People's Victory - Second Phase: An Analysis of 1972 Elections. All India Congress Committee. New Delhi, India: 1972. (Box IN-66)
    - Political Profile of Andhra Pradesh: Parliament Result (1951-1984). Rao, G. S., andBbau, G. Venkat. New Delhi, [no publisher], India: 1989. (Box IN-66)
    - Presidential and Vice-Presidential Elections Act, 1952, With Rules. Ministry of Law, Justice and Company Affairs. New Delhi, Govt. of India, India: 1974. (Box IN-66)
    - Report of the Committee on Electoral Reform. Narayan, Jayaprakash. New Delhi, [no publisher]. India: 1975? (Box IN-66)
      Report of the Committee appointed by Mr. Jayaprakash Narayan on behalf of the citizens of Democracy.
    - Results of Bye-Elections Held between January, 1965 and July, 1966. Election Commission of India. Delhi, India: 1966. (Box IN-66)
    - Review of the Second General Elections. Central Committee Communist Party of India.New Delhi, India: 1957. (Box IN-66)
    - Voters Dilemma and Sarvodaya Approach, The. Deo, Sankarrao. Tanjore, Sarvodaya Prachuralaya, India: 1962. (Box IN-66)
      Brochure No.2.
    - Voting Behaviour in Assam Elections, 1985. Institute of Social Sciences. New Delhi, Institute of Social Sciences, India: 1986. (Box IN-66)
      Report of a Seminar. Pamphlet Series-2.
    - Voting Behaviour in Punjab Elections, 1985. Institute of Social Sciences. New Delhi, Institute of Social Sciences, India: 1986. (Box IN-66)
      Report of a Seminar. Pamphlet Series-1.
    - Your Questions Answered through Congress Election Manifesto. Indian National Congress. New Delhi, Indian National Congress Camp, India: 1970? (Box IN-66)
  - Employment, 1962-1990, 1 box
    The 29 pamphlets in this section were published by official government agencies and political parties. They discuss job training, employment policies, statistics, affirmative action, problems of employment, job training for the underprivileged, rural employment, and rules and regulations concerning retirement benefits for public and private services.
    - Central Universities Retirement Benefit Rules 1967. University Grants Commission. New Delhi, India: 1970. (Box IN-67)
      Containing General Provident Fund-cum-Pension-cum-Gratuity Rules and Contributory Provident Fund-cum-Gratuity Rules for the Central Universities and Indian Institute and Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore.
    - Contributory Provident Fund Rules, Central Services Rules, Contributory Provident Fund Rules, 1962, Central Services (India Provident Fund) (Sterling Accounts) Rules and Central Services (Remittances into and Payments from Provident Fund) Rules, 1960. India. Ministry of Finance. New Delhi, India: 1966. (Box IN-67)
    - Development of the Personnel Function in India. Banerjee, R. Calcutta, National Institute of Personnel Management, India: 1982. (Box IN-67)
      Monograph No.1.
    - Employees' Provident Fund at a Glance. Central Board for Workers' Education.Nagpur, Central Board for Workers' Education, India: 1966. (Box IN-67)
      C.B.W.E. Publication No. 45.
    - Employees' Provident Fund. India. Ministry of Information and Broadcasting. Delhi, India: 1962. (Box IN-67)
    - Employees' Provident Funds Acts and Scheme - Employers' Guide, The. Central Provident Fund Commissioner.Simla, Central Provident Fund Commissioner, India: 1965. (Box IN-67)
      A small guide-book containing the basic features of the Employees' Provident Funds Scheme.
    - Employment in India. India. Publications Division. Delhi, India: 1966. (Box IN-67)
    - Employment Oriented Plan for Kerala - Kerala's Draft Sixth Plan 1980-85. Kerala. Dept. of Public Relations. Trivaudrum, India: 1980. (Box IN-67)
    - Facing the Challenge. Indian National Congress. New Delhi, AICC Publication, India: 197-? (Box IN-67)
      Jobs for Millions.
    - Growth of Population and Induction of Employment Oriented Schemes in Haryana. Haryana. Planning Dept. Chandigarh, The Economic and Statistical Organisation, India: 1972. (Box IN-67)
    - India's Manpower Requirements - Some Preliminary Estimates. Directorate General of Employment and Training, Bangalore. Hyderabad, Dept. of Labour and Employment, India: 1969. (Box IN-67)
    - Job Reservation for the Economically Weak: Prime Minister's Statement. India. Ministry of Information and Broadcasting. New Delhi, Directorate of Advertising and Visual Publicity, India: 1990. (Box IN-67)
      Text of Statement of the Prime Minister, Shri V. P. Singh, made in Parliament, 27th August, 1990.
    - Jobs that Wait for You (Calling all Youngmen). Directorate of Information And Tourism.Bangalore, Director of Printing and Stationery. India: 1973. (Box IN-67)
    - More Employment Opportunities for the People. India. Ministry of Information and Broadcasting. New Delhi, Directorate of Advertising and Visual Publicity, India: 1983. (Box IN-67)
    - My Home, My Work Place. Sharma, Bina. Ahmedabad, Self-Employed Women's Association (SEWA) and The Gandhi Labour Institute, India: 1987. (Box IN-67)
      Workshop Report on Home-based piece rate workers.
    - Plan for Full Employment. Swamy, Subramanian. Delhi, Bharatiya Jana Sangh, India: 1970. (Box IN-67)
      Presented at the Jana Sangh Study Group, Chandigarh, July 20, 1970.
    - Poverty and Unemployment. Indian Council of Social Science Research. New Delhi, India: 1976. (Box IN-67)
      Sponsored Research Programme.
    - Problem of Unemployment. Janata Party Publication. New Delhi, India: 198-? (Box IN-67)
    - Report on Employment Aspects of the Bhilai Steel Project (1956-1962). Madhya Pradesh, Labour Department. India: 1964. (Box IN-177 (oversize))
    - Report on Survey of Employment and Unemployment. Union Territory of Pondicherry. Pondicherry. Bureau of Statistics and Evaluation, India: 1973. (Box IN-67)
    - Rural Unemployment and Employment in Uttar Pradesh during 1958-59 Uttar Pradesh. Economics and Statistics Dept. .Lucknow, Directorate of Economics and Statistics. India: 1967. (Box IN-67)
    - Struggle for Survival: Organizing the Paper Pickers of Ahemdabad. Self Employed Women's Association. Ahmedabad, Self-Employed Women's Association (SEWA), India: 1988. (Box IN-67)
    - Study on Working of Apprenticeship Training Scheme at the Hindustan Shipyard, Visakhapatnam and The Allwyn Metal Works, Hyderabad. Hyderabad. State Evaluation Committee. Hyderabad, Director of Printing and Stationery, India: 1969. (Box IN-67)
      Evaluation Series No. 14.
    - Study on Working of Employment Information and Assistance Bureaux in Rural Areas. Hyderabad. State Evaluation Committee. Hyderabad, Director of Printing and Stationery, India: 1969. (Box IN-67)
      Evaluation Series No. 4.
    - Study on Working of Evening Classes at Hindustan Shipyard, Visakhapatnam. Hyderabad. State Evaluation Committee. Hyderabad, Director of Printing and Stationery, India: 1969. (Box IN-67)
      Evaluation Series No. 13.
    - Subsidised Employment Programmes - Half a Million Job Programmes. Bangalore. Directorate of Industries and Commerce. Bangalore, Govt. of Mysore, India: 197-? (Box IN-67)
    - Towards Self-Reliance - Employment Opportunities. India. Ministry of Information and Broadcasting. New Delhi, Directorate of Advertising and Visual Publicity, India: 1972. (Box IN-67)
    - Unemployment in India. Nehru, B. K., and Suri, K. B., and Lal, S. N. Bombay, Forum of Free Enterprise, India: 1971. (Box IN-67)
    - Urban Employment and Unemployment in Uttar Pradesh (1961-62). Uttar Pradesh. Directorate of Economics and Statistics. Lucknow, Govt. of Uttar Pradesh, India: 1966. (Box IN-67)
      Bulletin No. 84.
    - Who is Responsible for this Unemployment? All India Congress Committee. New Delhi, AICC Publication, India: 1971. (Box IN-67)
      2.5 Crores Jobless.
  - Energy, 1963-1991, 2 boxes